

ABHINAV S NAIR

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

Phone: +91 7012185604

Email: abhinavsnvvh@gmail.com

Website: https://abhinavsnbz.github.

io/portfolio/

EDUCATION

2017 - 2021

APJ ABDUL KALAM
TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY

HEERA COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING AND TECHNOLOGY B.Tech Mechanical

2015-2017

SNVHSS ANAD

HIGHER SECONDARY Computer Science

SKILLS

Technical Skills

- Languages: Dart, HTML, CSS
- State Management: GetX, Provider, Bloc
- Databases: SQLite, Hive, Firebase Firestore
- API Integration: REST API, Firebase
- · Version Control: Git, GitHub
- Development Tools: Android Studio, Visual Studio Code
- UI/UX: Responsive Design, Material Design, Cupertino Styling
- Performance Optimization and Debugging

Soft Skills

- Problem-solving
- Team collaboration
- Effective communication

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a passionate Flutter Developer with over 2 years of experience in mobile application development. I specialize in building clean, scalable, and high-performing applications, optimizing app performance, and integrating APIs. Additionally, I have knowledge of web development technologies like HTML and CSS and continuously strive to learn new tools and techniques to stay ahead in the industry.

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2023 - Present

BzAnalytics Private Limited

Associate Software Developer

- Worked on development of user interface of Chatbot Application which uses GETX as STATEMANAGEMENT and Hive Database.
- Worked on a maintanance of an app which developed before the NULL SAFETY concept in Flutter.
- Worked on a body joint detection app with AI team which was used to detect the body joints and calculate the angle between them with the help of MEDIAPIPE and PROVIDER STATEMANAGEMENT
- Worked on a Learnig Management System developed for preparing competetive exam like PSC, SSC etc.
 Technologies used: Flutter, Getx, Firebase OTP Authentication, Youtube Explode, Videoplayer
- Developed app called LOVE BIRDS which is a Event Management Process with authentication and QR Code scanning functionality Technologies used: Flutter, BLOC, Mobile Scanner, Sqflite

January 2023 - April 2023

BzAnalytics Private Limited

Intern

 Collaborated with a team to design, develop, and test crossplatform mobile applications using Flutter.